mercury.com.au 2017-09-22

# Privacy Policy | Mercury

Mercury Group of Companies Pty Ltd (“Mercury”, “we”, “us”, “our”) is committed to your privacy and complies with the State and Federal Privacy Laws including the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and the Australian Privacy Principles

This Privacy Policy summarises how we handle your personal information. We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time by updating this page. The revised Privacy Policy will take effect when it is posted on our website.

By choosing to become a client of Mercury you can be assured that all personal and sensitive information you provide to us will be respected and kept secure in accordance with the law and this Privacy Policy. By using our services, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy.

#### Information Mercury collects and holds

_A Definition of Personal Information_

Personal information is defined by the Commonwealth Privacy Act 1988 as “Information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable: (a) whether the information or opinion is true or not; and (b) whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form or not.” It may range from the very sensitive (e.g. medical history or condition) to the more common (e.g. address, phone number and date of birth). It would include the opinion of others about your work performance (whether true or not), your work experience and qualifications, aptitude test results and other information obtained by us in connection with your possible employment.

_A Definition of Sensitive Information_

Sensitive information is a special category of personal information and includes information or opinion about your:

  * Racial or ethnic origin;
  * Political opinion;
  * Membership of a political association or religious beliefs, affiliations or philosophical beliefs;
  * Membership of a professional or trade association or membership of a trade union;
  * Sexual preferences or practices;
  * Police record;
  * Health or disability (at any time);
  * Expressed wishes about the future provisions of health services

From time to time, Mercury may collect certain of your personal and sensitive information only in connection with the purpose for which it was collected as being reasonably necessary for or related to Mercury’s business.

Generally, the only personal information we collect about you is that which you choose to tell us, or which you authorise us to obtain. The type of information we collect includes, your name, address, telephone number, employment history, police history (if any), entitlement to work in Australia and billing information. We may also use your personal information to verify information you have given to us or our customers, or to comply with the law.

_How do we collect and hold your personal information?_

Where possible, we will collect your personal information directly from you.  
Personal and sensitive information will be collected from you when:

  * You provide it to us directly;
  * We undertake or receive any personal, professional or academic reference about you;
  * We receive any results of inquiries that we might make of your former employers, colleagues or associates;
  * We receive any performance feedback (whether positive or negative);
  * We undertake psychological or medical assessments;
  * We undertake National Police History Checks and other pre-employment checks.

From time to time, with your consent, we may also collect personal information from third parties including ACIC (Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission, formally known as CrimTrac), Australian Federal Police, General Information Services Inc., RISQ Group, Dun & Bradstreet (Australia) Pty Ltd, Accurate Information Systems LLC, Australian Securities & Investments Commission and Australian Health Practitioner Regulation Agency.

Mercury has established appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard any information we collect. This helps prevent unauthorised access, maintains data accuracy and ensures that the information is used correctly. All data transferred to and from the Mercury servers are encrypted via a 1024bit SSL certificate and a hardware and software firewall is in place to prevent intrusion. All data stored within the Mercury’s systems can only be accessed by authorised staff members and the hosting facility.

_The purpose for which we collect, hold, use and disclose personal information._

We collect personal information that we consider relevant, and which is outlined in your written authority, for the purpose of providing our services. Sensitive information, in most cases, can only be disclosed with your written consent. Any personal information collected about an individual will not be used or disclosed for the purposes of direct marketing unless the individual has given Mercury consent to do so. Any personal information collected about an individual will not be disclosed to any overseas recipients, unless the individual has given Mercury consent to do so.

Some of the ways we use personal information include:

  * Communicate with you and others as part of our core business.
  * Send you important information regarding changes to our policies, other terms and conditions, On-line Services and other administrative issues.
  * Prevent, detect and investigate crime, including fraud and money laundering, and analyse and manage other commercial risks.
  * Carry out market research and analysis, including satisfaction surveys.
  * Provide marketing information to you including information about other products and services offered by Mercury provided consent has been given to do so.
  * Manage our infrastructure and business operations, and comply with internal policies and procedures, including those relating to auditing; accounting; billing and collections; IT systems; data and website hosting; business continuity; and records, document and print management.
  * Resolve complaints, and handle requests for data access or correction.
  * Comply with applicable laws and regulatory obligations (including laws outside your country of residence), such as those relating to anti-money laundering, sanctions and anti-terrorism; comply with legal process; and respond to requests from public and governmental authorities (in outside your country of residence).
  * Establish and defend legal rights; protect our operations or those of any of our group companies or insurance business partners, our rights or property, and/or that of our group companies, you or others; and pursue available remedies or limit our damages.
  * Assess your suitability for employment positions and contact you to notify you of potential employment opportunities within our Executive Recruitment business.

_What happens if you don’t provide all this information?_

If you do not provide some or all of the personal information requested, we may not be able to provide you with the benefit of our services.

_Using a pseudonym or engaging with us anonymously_

Where practicable, you will be given the opportunity to engage with us on an anonymous basis or using a pseudonym. Due to the nature of our services, in most cases, anonymity will not be possible.

_To whom does Mercury disclose your personal information?_

We may disclose your personal information to:

  * potential employers
  * with consent, credit agencies
  * with consent, criminal history information providers
  * government authorities (where required by law)
  * third parties involved in court action (where required by law)
  * other parties that provide support services to our services
  * Professional advisers
  * Potential business partners or purchasers

_Website cookies and usage information_

When you access our website, we may use software embedded in our website (such as Javascript) and we may place small data files (or cookies) on your computer or other device to collect information about which pages you view and how you reach them, what you do when you visit a page, the length of time you remain on the page, and how we perform in providing content to you. A cookie does not identify individuals personally, but it does identify computers.

You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie and this will provide you with an opportunity to either accept or reject it in each instance. We may gather your IP address as part of our business activities and to assist with any operational difficulties or support issues with our services. This information does not identify you personally.

_Opting out of direct marketing communications_

Where we use your personal information to send you marketing and promotional information by post, email or telephone, we will provide you with an opportunity to opt-out of receiving such information. By electing not to opt-out, we will assume we have your implied consent to receive similar information and communications in the future. We will always ensure that our opt-out notices are clear, conspicuous and easy to take up. If you wish to opt out of communications from Mercury, please use the contact details below.

_How an individual access their personal information held by Mercury_

If an individual wishes to exercise their rights of access or alternatively has any questions or believes that any personal information held by Mercury is incorrect or incomplete, the individual can write to our Privacy Officer at the address below.

Mercury will then take all reasonable steps to correct the information or if necessary discuss alternative actions with the individual.

Personal information will only be released to the individual directly, unless we are provided with a written, signed authority by individual to provide it to a third party.

_Updating your personal information_

You may ask us to update, correct or delete the personal information we hold about you at any time. We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making any corrections to or deletion of your information. We also have obligations to take reasonable steps to correct personal information we hold when we are satisfied that it is inaccurate, out- of-date, incomplete, irrelevant or misleading for the purpose for which it is held. If you wish to update your personal information, please use the contact details below.

_How can you contact Mercury regarding privacy?_

If an individual would like to make further inquiries or complain about a breach of the Australian Privacy Principles, or complain about a registered Australian Privacy Principles code (if any) that may relate Mercury’s business, the individual can contact our Privacy Officer at the address:  
Privacy Officer  
119 Cecil Street, South Melbourne, Victoria 3205

Mercury will take all complaints regarding privacy of information seriously. We will respond to any requests, questions, or complaints as soon as possible in a reasonable time frame.

If you do not provide us with all or part of the personal information we require, it may prevent us from providing services, which may impact on your application for employment with our customers.
